miramagia.us 2011-05-16

# Privacy Policy of Travian Publishing GmbH

                                Privacy Policy of Travian Publishing GmbH
This is the Privacy Policy of Travian Publishing GmbH, Wilhelm-Wagenfeld-Str. 22, 80807 Munich,
Germany (hereinafter: “TRAVIAN PUBLISHING“). It applies to all websites and games operated by
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING and/or by its subsidiaries.
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING shall handle all personal data which the user submits during the business
relations strictly confidentially in compliance with all applicable data protection regulations. Details
are provided in this Privacy Policy.
In the event that a link contained on the website operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING redirects the
user to another website not operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING draws the
user's attention to the fact that the present Privacy Policy does not apply to this third-party website.
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING is not responsible for how the operator of this website handles user data. In
particular, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING is not responsible for the website not operated by TRAVIAN
PUBLISHING not having same data protection standards as those that TRAVIAN PUBLISHING offers its
users. Hence, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING recommends the user to carefully read the privacy policies of
linked websites.
Which personal data does TRAVIAN PUBLISHING collect, use and store?
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING collects, processes and stores the personal data which the user voluntarily
submits to TRAVIAN PUBLISHING by electronic or other means of communication (e.g. in standard
forms or otherwise on the websites and games operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING).
This includes data which the user provides to other users when communicating with them on the
websites and games operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING.
In order to register for the use of the games operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING or in order to
purchase a premium membership, the user must provide certain personal details, including his email
address. If the user would like to purchase a premium membership for a user fee, this means that
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING will require further information from the user, such as his postal address, bank
account and/or credit card information.
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING advises the user to handle his data carefully and sparingly and to carefully
consider what and with whom he would like to communicate via the websites and games operated
by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING. Certain information, e.g. communications between users, is also visible for
other users of the websites and games operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING.
Here are some examples of data stored by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING:
When a user accesses the websites and games operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING, TRAVIAN
PUBLISHING automatically stores the domain name and/or the IP-address of the computer via which
the user contacts TRAVIAN PUBLISHING, the date and the length of time spent on the websites and
games operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING and the pages of the websites and games operated by
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING accessed by the user.
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING stores the user's email address. TRAVIAN PUBLISHING may use it to send
newsletters and information on the games of TRAVIAN PUBLISHING to the user. The user may, of
course, revoke his consent at any time in writing (e.g. by email) without incurring any costs, apart
from the costs of transmitting the written revocation (at base rates). The user shall be given the
opportunity in all information sent by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING and in every newsletter to refuse to
accept further information and to dispatch an appropriate revocation.
What does TRAVIAN PUBLISHING do with the user's data?
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING collects, processes and stores the personal data of the user only insofar as
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING assumes that this reasonably serves legal business purposes. In other words:
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING collects, processes and stores the data of users so that TRAVIAN PUBLISHING
can better understand the users of the websites and games operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING and

thus offer them better services. For example, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING may not only use the stored data
to directly process the licence agreement including all related possibilities of use (e.g. use of the
games; participation in services related to the games; use of the services provided by customer
support) but also in order to detect malfunctions or the abuse of websites and games operated by
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING.
For this reason, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING will collect and store records which reflect how the websites
and games operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING are used, e.g. in-game user activities and in-game
communication between users or communication within game-related services. This includes the
monitoring of playing patterns and checks for possible manipulations of game operations which can
then serve to detect abusive or improper activities of users. TRAVIAN PUBLISHING uses special
programs to detect infringements of the rules of the games, e.g. programs which can detect the use
of unauthorized scripts and which can store the IP address and other data which the browser
transfers as header information. Should TRAVIAN PUBLISHING discover that a user is acting in breach
of his contractual obligations, e.g. by using unauthorized scripts, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING expressly
reserves the right to merge the IP address of the respective user with other data which TRAVIAN
PUBLISHING has on this user in order to bring the infringement to the attention of the user. TRAVIAN
PUBLISHING might then take further steps against the respective user in order to restore regular
game operations.
For the purpose of handling payments, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING has the right to disclose user data to
service providers instructed to collect the user fee insofar as this is necessary for the calculation of
the fee and for settlement with the user. Furthermore, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING is entitled to provide
user data to third parties to whom receivables due to TRAVIAN PUBLISHING from the user have been
assigned provided that this is necessary to collect the receivables. TRAVIAN PUBLISHING shall inform
the user of the names of such third parties. If TRAVIAN PUBLISHING cooperates with third parties in
order to provide its services, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING shall oblige such parties to comply with applicable
data protection laws and to ensure adequate data protection.
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING may also use the information provided by or stored on the user purely for
internal checks as regards demography, user interests and user behaviour. This use is carried out
anonymized. TRAVIAN PUBLISHING may also statistically evaluate information on the user in an
anonymized and aggregated form for advertising and market research. If and as far as TRAVIAN
PUBLISHING uses user data to create user profiles, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING shall never pass on such
profiles without the prior consent of the user and shall immediately stop such utilization of user
profiles if the user objects to such use of his data.
Only after their prior consent shall TRAVIAN PUBLISHING enable third parties to contact the user for
advertising purposes. As long as the user does not object, his user data may also be used for sending
the user advertising messages which reflect his interests (based on the information he has submitted
to TRAVIAN PUBLISHING and on his actions within the websites and games operated by TRAVIAN
PUBLISHING).
What other data do we collect and how are they used?
Your web browser or your client software transfers geographic data, information on your computer
(e.g. performance data, gaming data processing, type of browser) and data on the use of our
products and services (e.g. time of login and logout). TRAVIAN PUBLISHING uses these data to create
summary statistics of its community. Furthermore, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING can use these data for
purposes of security and system integrity (e.g. to prevent hacking and cheating) or for purposes of
prosecution. Please note that the use of your data may vary depending on the product and/or on the
service. Please check the documentation of your game. TRAVIAN PUBLISHING shall sometimes relate
this information to your personal data, if TRAVIAN PUBLISHING is of the opinion that our Terms of
Use have been infringed or if TRAVIAN PUBLISHING is ordered to do so by prosecuting authorities.

TRAVIAN PUBLISHING will also request you to enter a user name and a password. TRAVIAN
PUBLISHING requests you not to use your real name, the name of another person or the name of a
protected brand as a user name.
If you are a registered user, your details in TRAVIAN PUBLISHING databases can be stored to adjust
the website to your specifications, to transmit user-specific information on TRAVIAN PUBLISHING, its
partners or third-party providers or for other business purposes.
What are IP (internet protocol) addresses and how does TRAVIAN PUBLISHING use these?
An Internet Protocol ("IP")-address is a unique identification number assigned to your server or the
server of your Internet service provider ("ISP"). TRAVIAN PUBLISHING ascertains IP-addresses in
certain cases for purposes of system management, account authentication and system
administration. TRAVIAN PUBLISHING might also use IP-addresses to restrict access to the servers of
the company and to exclude individual systems so that the abuse of these servers is prevented.
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING might use these IP-addresses in connection with the data of a certain account
or user if TRAVIAN PUBLISHING is of the opinion that our Terms of Use have been infringed or if
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING is requested to do so by a judicial authority.
Assignment of processors
We treat your data strictly confidentially and do not disclose them to external third-parties.
However, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING might be legally obliged to disclose your data in individual cases,
such as to investigating authorities, whereby data are then only disclosed as far as required by law.
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING shall engage subsidiaries or sister companies or third parties to provide
services on our behalf in an individual case. By assignment of TRAVIAN PUBLISHING, Travian Games
GmbH, situated in Munich (Germany), processes all payment support services. The assignment of
processors further applies to payment processing via external service providers (Paypal, Global
Collect etc.). These external companies are obliged to treat your data confidentially, safely and in
accordance with the law and may only use your data insofar as this is required to perform their task.
In all cases, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING remains the controller.
Amendments to or deletion of personal data
The user may change his personal data at any time (e.g. in order to update or correct such data) or
delete his personal data completely. If the user would like TRAVIAN PUBLISHING to change his
personal data or to stop using his data, the user may contact TRAVIAN PUBLISHING at
privacy@travianpublishing.com.
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING will then make the required changes or delete the user data as quickly as
possible. However, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING points out to the user that for technical or organizational
reasons, some measures may still be carried out after the user has submitted his request for
deletion, if such measures had already been initiated but not completed by that time.
Information on personal data
Upon request, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING shall notify the user without delay of all personal data saved on
him free of charge. This information will usually be provided electronically, normally by email.
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING reserves the right to amend this Privacy Policy at any time, however TRAVIAN
PUBLISHING shall always observe the respectively applicable laws on data protection. TRAVIAN
PUBLISHING advises users to obtain information on the current Privacy Policy each time they visit
websites and games. If TRAVIAN PUBLISHING would like to use the personal data of users to a

greater extent than previously, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING shall, of course, notify users thereof in
advance.
Should you have any general questions on this Privacy Policy and on data protection at TRAVIAN
PUBLISHING, please do not hesitate to contact us at the addresses shown below. Please state your
user ID, email address and, if appropriate, the game played.
Data protection: privacy@travianpublishing.com
Alternatively, you can send inquiries to our postal address:
Travian Publishing GmbH
Wilhelm- Wagenfeld- Strasse 22
80807 Munich
Germany
Information for parents
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING is well aware that we bear a special responsibility for personal data provided
to us by children. Hence, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING recommends that parents tell their children never to
actually enter their real names, addresses or telephone numbers without obtaining their parents' or
their guardian's consent.
Children aged between 13 and 17 should ask their parents to read through these basic principles on
personal rights and contact us if they would like to use the possibilities we have of restricting services
or of voicing any concerns.
Minors under 18 may not register online for services subject to a charge without obtaining the prior
consent of their parents or guardian. We kindly request parents and guardians to be particularly
vigilant to ensure that their children do not break any laws while they use our websites or online
services.
If you use services offered within the framework of the listed TRAVIAN PUBLISHING websites, you
agree to the principles of TRAVIAN PUBLISHING concerning personal rights. If you do not agree to
these principles, you should not use the services offered on these websites.
How safe are your personal data?
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING believes that it goes without saying that the data that you send us are
protected and remain unchanged in their original form. Access to personal data is strictly monitored
for this purpose. In addition, TRAVIAN PUBLISHING will do its utmost to ensure that subsidiaries and
third-party providers, to whom TRAVIAN PUBLISHING might transfer your data, treat you with the
same respect and focus on data security.
Third-party websites

Our websites might contain advertising or services which are linked to other websites, such as
Twitter, Facebook and YouTube. The fact that TRAVIAN PUBLISHING creates a link to a website, does
not constitute any endorsement, approval or opinion concerning our relation to this third party. If
you click on the link to the website of a third party - which includes advertisements - you leave the
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING website you have accessed and change to the selected website. As TRAVIAN
PUBLISHING has no control at all over the activities of third parties, we refuse to accept any
responsibility whatsoever for the use of your personal data by such third parties. Furthermore,
TRAVIAN PUBLISHING cannot guarantee that such third parties follow the same data protection and
security practices as TRAVIAN PUBLISHING. You should therefore read through the data protection
regulations of all other service providers whose services you use. Should you access the website of a
third party which is linked to a TRAVIAN PUBLISHING website, you should first note the data
protection regulations of this website before you disclose any personal information.
Products offered in cooperation with third parties
Users can register for other services from our website/websites. Certain products and/or services
available on our website are offered to you in cooperation with third parties and might require that
you state information serving to identify you, to register for those products and/or services and to
ensure access to those products and/or services. Those products and/or services identify the third
parties upon registration. If you register for those products and/or services the information serving
to identify you is disclosed to those third parties and is subject to the data protection regulations and
methods of those third parties. TRAVIAN PUBLISHING assumes no responsibility for the data
protection regulations and methods of those third parties. For this reason, you should note the data
protection regulations and methods of those third parties before you provide the information serving
to identify you in connection with those products and/or services.
Glossary
To make this Privacy Policy easier to understand, the most important terms are briefly explained
below:
What are personal data?
Personal data are data which identify the user. These data can be used to contact the user in reality
or to locate him. These data include, for example, the user's correct name, email address, telephone
number, postal address or credit card data.
What are user data?
User data are data which are collected, processed and stored by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING when a user
contacts the websites and games operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING. Above all, user data are
characteristics serving to identify the user (e.g. the domain name and/or the IP-address of the
computer via which the user contacts TRAVIAN PUBLISHING), information on the start and end and
on the scope of the respective use of the websites and games operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING and
information on the accessed pages of the websites and games operated by TRAVIAN PUBLISHING.
Last revised: 15 March 2011
